Guide to the Elmer Holmes Bobst Collection MSS.067
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Film, Audio and Video Tape, Slides and Recordings.
  - Cancer Appeal on Henry Morgan Show, April 8, 1948; cuid28907 (Box 57)
  - Christmas Greetings Governor Driscoll, Undated; cuid28908 (Box 57)
  - Mr. E. H. Bobst interviewed by H. Manning on CKGM, Montreal, November 11, 1960; cuid28909 (Box 57)
  - Hahnemann Medical College and Hospital Bobst Dedication Dinner, Undated; cuid28910 (Box 57)
  - Greetings to the International Association of Gerontology from Members of the Gerontological Society in New York, March 25, 1955; cuid28911 (Box 57)
  - Hahnemann Medical College and Hospital Bobst Dedication Dinner, Undated; cuid28912 (Box 57)
  - Greetings to the International Association of Gerontology from Members of the Gerontological Society in New York, March 25, 1955; cuid28913 (Box 57)
  - State Dept., O.I.C., Mr. Elmer H. Bobst "Cancer Control in America", Undated; cuid28914 (Box 57)
  - Mr. Bobst Christmas Message, 1952; cuid28915 (Box 57)
  - Mr. Bobst Christmas Message, 1952; cuid28916 (Box 57)
  - Xmas Message 1954 by Mr. Elmer Bobst, cuid28917 (Box 57)
  - Who Has Made You, You Beautiful Forest, Undated; cuid28918 (Box 57)
  - Special Cancer Show Mr. Bobst Talk, April 3, 1950; cuid28919 (Box 57)
  - Cancer Drive Mr. Bobst, April 9, 1948; cuid28920 (Box 57, Disc Part 1, Disc Part 2, Disc Part 3)
  - Untitled, Undated; cuid28921 (Box 57)
  - Untitled, Undated; cuid28922 (Box 57)
  - Untitled, Undated; cuid28923 (Box 57)
  - American Cancer Society Kickoff Show, March 31, 1947; cuid28924 (Box 57)
  - Mr. Bobst, December 14, 1951; cuid28925 (Box 58)
  - Mr. Bobst, December 13, 1951; cuid28926 (Box 58)
  - Christmas Message (Elmer H. Bobst), December 22, 1950; cuid28927 (Box 58, Disc Part 1, Disc Part 2)
  - Elmer H. Bobst Talk on Mutual Broadcasting System Easter PGM, April 6, 1947; cuid28928 (Box 58)
  - Pharmacy Week Program, April 23, 1947; cuid28929 (Box 58, Disc Part 2, Disc Part 3)
  - Christmas Message to Employees, December 14, 1951; cuid28930 (Box 58)
  - American Cancer Society (Elmer H. Bobst), August 3, 1955; cuid28931 (Box 58)
  - American Cancer Society (Elmer H. Bobst), August 31, 1953; cuid28932 (Box 58)
  - Christmas Message, December 22, 1950; cuid28933 (Box 58, Disc Part 1, Disc Part 2)
  - Xmas Message 1954 by Mr. Elmer Bobst, cuid28934 (Box 58, Disc Part 1, Disc Part 2, Disc Part 3, Disc Part 4)
  - This I Believe: A Series of Radio Broadcasts by Edward R. Murrow and Guests: No. 7A Series 3, Undated; cuid28935 (Box 58)
  - Official Album: Inaugural Ceremonies of Richard M. Nixon, 37th President of the United States of America, January 20, 1969; cuid28936 (Box 58)
  - If I'm Elected: Our Presidents and Their Opponents [1892-1952]: Narration by John Carradine: Part Two, cuid28937 (Box 58)
  - Gallatin Award (Elmer Holmes Bobst), December 8, 1966; cuid28938 (Box 58, Disc Part 1, Disc Part 2)
  - State Department, O.I.C.: Mr. Elmer H. Bobst: "Cancer Control in America", Undated; cuid28939 (Box 58)
- Series VI: Miscellaneous Items and Oversize.
  Series VI includes artifacts and art Bobst collected on the pharmaceutical industry, items from Bobst's yachts, framed photographs inscribed to him, and furnishings from his office.
  - Ship's bell from the yacht Dodo, undated; MSS.067.cuid20239 (Box 92)
  - Section of ship's keel from the yacht Alisa V, undated; MSS.067.cuid20240 (Box 93)
  - War memorabilia in Japanese box., undated; MSS.067.cuid20241 (Box 93)
  - Ship's clock presented to Elmer Holmes Bobst., undated; MSS.067.cuid20242 (Box 99)
  - Ship's barometer., undated; MSS.067.cuid20243 (Box 96)
  - Chart for cruise of the Alisa IV, 1951; MSS.067.cuid20244 (Folder 12, left)
  - Framed photo of Elmer Bobst with President Eisenhower, undated; MSS.067.cuid20329 (Box 68)
  - Framed reproduction of Bernard Baruch portrait and handwritten note, 1954; MSS.067.cuid20330 (Box 65)
  - Framed photo of Mr. Bobst with President Nixon, undated; MSS.067.cuid20331 (Box 64)
  - Frame photo of Mr. and Mrs. Bobst on Library construction site, undated; MSS.067.cuid20332 (Box 64)
  - Framed photograph of Elmer Holmes Bobst's 85th birthday at the White House with the Nixons, undated; MSS.067.cuid20333 (Box 69)
  - Framed certificate from US Treasury, 1945; MSS.067.cuid20334 (Box 67)
  - Framed photograph of the yacht Alisa V, undated; MSS.067.cuid20335 (Box 66)
  - Framed oil portrait of Mr. Bobst, undated; MSS.067.cuid20336 (Item MSS.067.cuid20336)
  - Framed black and white photo of the Hoffman-LaRoche Building, undated; MSS.067.cuid20337 (Box 70)
  - Ceramic figuring of man in yellow military attire, undated; MSS.067.cuid20340 (Box 79)
  - White molded glass "ADEPS BENZ", undated; MSS.067.cuid20343 (Box 76)
  - White molded glass jar "UNG. IODOFORM', undated; MSS.067.cuid20341 (Box 77)
  - Ceramic jar "OXID: FERR: R: C:", undated; MSS.067.cuid20342 (Box 72)
  - ceramic jar "PACATAL", gilded lettering, undated; MSS.067.cuid20344 (Box 60)
  - ceramic jar "Pacatal", blue lettering, undated; MSS.067.cuid20345 (Box 60)
  - ceramic jar "Peritrate", blue lettering, undated; MSS.067.cuid20346 (Box 60)
  - ceramic jar "Gelusil", blue lettering, undated; MSS.067.cuid20347 (Box 60)
  - Ceramic apothecary jar "I irios D F en Polvo", undated; MSS.067.cuid20348 (Box 73)
  - bronze mortar and pestle, from Columbia University College of Pharmacy, 1957; MSS.067.cuid20349 (Box 80)
  - Ceramic apothecary jar "Unguento Rosado", undated; MSS.067.cuid20351 (Box 74)
  - Ceramic apothecary jar "Farmacia Central: Estoraq", undated; MSS.067.cuid20352 (Box 82)
  - Ceramic apothecary jar "Farmacia el Amparo: Aguedita", undated; MSS.067.cuid20353 (Box 75)
  - Ceramic apothecary jar "Farmacia el Amparo: Oxalico", undated; MSS.067.cuid20354 (Box 83)
  - Ceramic figure of man in blue and red military attire, undated; MSS.067.cuid20355 (Box 78)
  - Glass jar "syr. rhei. ar", undated; MSS.067.cuid20356 (Box 98)
  - Glass jar "pot. bichro", undated; MSS.067.cuid20357 (Box 100)
  - Glass jar "tinct. sanguin", undated; MSS.067.cuid20358 (Box 100)
  - Brown blown glass jar, undated; MSS.067.cuid20359 (Box 98)
  - greenish clear blown glass jar, undated; MSS.067.cuid20360 (Box 59)
  - greenish clear blown glass jar, undated; MSS.067.cuid20361 (Box 59)
  - globe shaped blown glass pill container with pills, undated; MSS.067.cuid20362 (Box 59)
  - unmarked mortar and pestle, undated; MSS.067.cuid20363 (Box 81)
  - Bronze sculpture of lion eating rabbit on top of faux wood base, undated; MSS.067.cuid20364 (Item MSS.067.cuid20364)
  - Side table with three drawers, undated; MSS.067.cuid20365 (Item MSS.067.cuid20365)
  - framed photograph of Mrs. Bobst, undated; MSS.067.cuid20366 (Box 63)
  - pen and clock set from Dick Nixon, 1957; MSS.067.cuid20367 (Box 27)
  - Elmer H. Bost Award Contributing to Arts and Letters, undated; MSS.067.cuid20368 (Box 26)
  - area rug, undated; MSS.067.cuid20369 (Item MSS.067.cuid20369)
  - upholstered chair (salmon upholstery), undated; MSS.067.cuid20370 (Item MSS.067.cuid20370)
  - Mr. Bobst's desk, undated; MSS.067.cuid20371 (Item MSS.067.cuid20371)
  - small side desk, undated; MSS.067.cuid20372 (Item MSS.067.cuid20372)
  - Mr. Bobst's chair, undated; MSS.067.cuid20373 (Item MSS.067.cuid20373)
  - globe with wood stand, undated; MSS.067.cuid20374 (Item MSS.067.cuid20374)
  - Booklet: "Some Stirring Relics of Historical Times", 1938; MSS.067.cuid20375 (Box 89)
  - Boxed Booklet: "Ionosphere, The Nearness of Distance." Eastern Airlines, 1975; MSS.067.cuid20376 (Box 89)
  - Elmer Holmes Bobst. Portrait, framed, 1940; MSS.067.cuid20377 (Box 105)
  - Roche, Inc. With an image of Elmer Holmes Bobst. Print, framed. By Dante V. DeFlorio, undated; MSS.067.cuid20378 (Box 97)
  - Nixon Presidential Library certificate and letter, framed., 1989-02-01; MSS.067.cuid20386 (Box 94)
  - Richard M. Nixon. Photograph Portrait, undated; MSS.067.cuid20381 (Box 95)
  - High School Diploma, Lititz, Pa., 1901-05-30; MSS.067.cuid20383 (Box 95)
  - Elmer Bobst Insurance Certificates, 1919-03-13; 1977-05-25; 1917-03-13; MSS.067.cuid21311 (Box 95)
  - University Heights, New York University. Print, framed, 1967-06-22; MSS.067.cuid20379 (Box 97)
- Series VII: Books and Periodicals Belonging to Elmer Holmes Bobst.
  Series VII contains selected books from Bobst's personal library, including family bibles. Also in this series are periodicals with articles by or about Bobst.
  - Subseries A: Books (Box 47, Box 48, Box 49, Box 51, Box 52, Box 53, Box 54, Box 55, Box 56, Box 106)
    - Addison, Joseph. The Spectator. v. 8 London., 1738
    - Akimoto, S. Tokyo Miyage. Yokohama., 1912
    - Aristotle. Works. London., 1821
    - Art of Invigorating and Prolonging Life. Philadelphia, 1823
    - Bacon, Roger. The Cure of Old Age. London, 1638
    - Bible. [Holmes Family Bible], 1850
    - Bible. [Inscription: Harry Bobst, Christmas], 1898
    - Bible. New York. [Presentation: To Elmer Walton Bobst on his confirmation day by his grandfather, Isaac Bobst.], 1921
    - Chase, A.W. Chase's Recipes. Ann Arbor, Mi, 1866
    - Clough, S. DeWitt. Everyday Courage. Chicago, 1928
    - DeGomez. Persian Anecdotes. Trans. by Paul Chamberlain. London, 1730
    - Eisenhower, Julie Nixon. Eye on Nixon: A Photographic Study of the President and the Man. New York: Hawthorne Books, 1972
    - Everybody's Dictionary.
    - Fishbein, Morris. The Medical Follies. New York, 1925
    - Guide to Jesus. Philadelphia, 1899
    - Harris, John. A History of the First Inventors of the World. London, 1686
    - How to Make a Drugstore Pay Better. Philadelphia, 1894
    - Jackson, Robert. A Treatise of the Fevers of Jamaica. Philadelphia, 1795
    - The Key to Heaven. Winterberg, N.Y., 1905
    - Lamb, Charles. The Essays of Elia. New York, 1892
    - LLoyd's Register of American Yachts. New York, 1954
    - Moore, George. Use of the Body in Relation to the Mind. New York, 1847
    - Omar Khayyam. The Rubaiyat. Portland, Me, 1894
    - Poppen, James L. Peron the Man. s.l., 1955
    - Powell, Thomas. Pocket Formulary and Physicians Manual. Savannah, Ga., 1955
    - Roche Review. Nutley, N.J. v.1-7, 1936-1943
    - Tales of the Genii. Trans. by Charles Morell. London, 1857
    - Wallace, William. Boating. New York, 1954
    - Webster's Little Gem Dictionary. Springfield, Mass., 1924
    - Webster's New International Unabridged Dictionary. Springfield, Mass., 1960
    - The Wedding Service. Philadelphia, undated
    - Wilson, George. A Compleat Course of Chymistry. London, 1709
    - Wright, Isaac. Wright's Family Medicine. Madisonville, Tenn., 1833
  - Subseries B: Periodicals with articles about Elmer Holmes Bobst., 1943-1967 (Box 50)